Derrick Holleman

Minneapolis, MN (612) 418-5274 derrickholleman@gmail.com

Full Stack Software Engineer

Portfolio Website
GitHub
LinkedIn

I'm a full stack software engineer with a love for problem solving and collaborating with others. My skills include an expertise in front-end design, Javascript, React, Express and PostgreSQL. I have a great eye for detail and I enjoy developing websites that are both modern looking and user-friendly. My background as a professional musician gives me an appreciation and a knack for keeping an organized schedule, being a prompt communicator and making a meaningful connection with whoever I'm working with.

Skills

Front-end: HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, React Hooks, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

Back-end: Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Additional Tools: Git, Heroku, Netlify, Unit Testing with Mocha and Chai.js, creating RESTful APIs

Projects

Blackjack Game | Project Link GitHub Repo

- Developed a blackjack game that shows both player and dealer cards that also includes a point system for a more immersive gaming experience.
- Implemented code that includes the use of higher order array methods, manipulating randomness, complex logic broken up into many functions and extensive DOM manipulation.
- Built with: Javascript, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap. Hosted on Netlify.

Mock Submission Form | Front-end Github Repo Back-end Github Repo

- Designed a mock submission form which lets users submit data and see it displayed on the page.
- Implemented a RESTful API that allows for adding, deleting and editing information with instantaneous page updates when data has changed.
- Built with: React, Express, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, HTML

Pomodoro Timer | Project Link GitHub Repo

- Created an app which lets users easily develop healthy study habits using a time based system.
- Developed an interactive timer which lets users add time and remove time depending on their needs.
- Built with: React, Bootstrap, HTML. Hosted on Netlify.

Experience

Professional Guitarist

Minneapolis, MN

Self-employed

April 2019 - September 2021

- Played electric guitar in bands as a guitarist-for-hire for a wide range of events.
- Contributed ideas and music to client's music projects in a collaborative environment during studio sessions.
- Made a living in a highly competitive environment by using guitar skills, determination and an easy going, friendly attitude.

Maintenance Associate SuperValu

Brooklyn Park, MN *June 2014 - December 2019*

- Listened to and responded to management and customer needs when it came to the cleanliness of the store.
- Displayed an eye for detail while cleaning different areas of the store.

 Developed a great work ethic while having to gather carts in the harsh Minnesota (winter) weather conditions.

Education

Certificate, Software Engineering

Remote

Thinkful September 20

September 2021 - February 2022

- Learned industry best practices, with an up to date curriculum detailing front-end and back-end technologies.
- The program focused on HTML5, CSS3, Javascript (ES6), React, React Hooks, Node, Express, PostgreSQL and Data Structures and Algorithms.
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while being supported by a senior developer through periodic meetings and Q&A sessions.

BA, Music Performance Augsburg University Minneapolis, MN
January 2018 - May 2019

Music Performance St. Paul, MN McNally Smith College of Music (school closed December 2017) September 2014 - December 2017